# **DANIEL PHAM**

## **Software Engineer**

**\$4906948696** 

@ dangmiracle@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/dang-phamb9054a115

**♀** Vietnam

#### **SUMMARY**

Software Engineer working in a wide range of Java areas including software engineering, development, data management and analytics. Highly motivated professional with more than seven years experience in software engineering and programming. I have always been a fast learner and a hard worker. My strengths include analytical thinking skills, the ability to multitask and problem-solving abilities as well as good communication, interpersonal and organizational skills.

#### **SKILLS & STRENGTH**

#### **OS & Cloud**

- MacOS, Windows 7/10, Ubuntu/Linux/CentOS
- AWS, AliCloud, Azure, Kubernetess, Docker

### **Programming Languages**

#### Back-end:

- Java/Java EE, JSP/Servlet, Spring Boot
- NodeJS / NestJs Framwork
- Ruby 2.7 & Rail 5
- Blockchain/ Web3js
- Ethereum/ Binance Smart Chain/ Solana/ Polygon
- Microservice Architect
- SSO, OAuth (1.0, 2.0)
- Firebase
- WebSocket/ SocketIO

#### Front-end:

- HTML/ HTML5/ jQueryS/ CSS3, JSON/XML
- Bootstrap 4,5
- ReactJS / Angular.IO
- UI/UI: Photoshop, Figma

#### Web service

- Restful API
- RPC (remote procedure call)
- Message Broker Rabbit MQ

#### **Databases**

- MySQL
- Postgresql
- MongoDB/ Aws DynamoDB

#### Tools

#### IDE:

- IntelliJ/ RubyMine/ Webstome
- Visual Code
- Eclipse
- Notepad ++

#### Task management:

- Trello
- lira

#### Source code management:

- SourceTree
- Bitbucket, Git/GitFlow

#### **Methodologies**

- Agile/Scrum
- Waterfall
- SOLID

## **EXPERIENCE**

## 06/2021 - Ongoing

28th Floor, OPAL Tower, 92 Nguyen Huu Canh Street, Ward 22, Binh Thanh District, Ho Chi Minh City,VN

## Technical Lead

## Unifiedpost

Unifiedpost is a leading cloud-based platform for SME business services built on Documents, Identity, Payments and associated finance services.

### My responsibility:

- ${\boldsymbol{\cdot}}$   $\,$  Production deployment's and provide solutions for technical issues
- Mentor and training for junior developers
- Review code & communicate importance about readability and quality of code (a fix should not create another problem somewhere else)
- Set up clear standards and procedures of development
- Introduce clear instructions on a daily basis
- Working with BA and CTO to prevent issues from arising and seek new business opportunities
- Support continuous improvement by investigating alternatives and technologies and presenting these for architectural review
- Motivate the team and create a good atmosphere for constructive feedback
- · Work on team building and foster good communication between team members

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### 06/2019 - 06/2021

3 Lim Teck Kim Rd, Genting Centre, Singapore 088934

#### 05/2017 - 05/2019

No. 217 Nam Ky Khoi Nghia Street Ward 7 Dist.3, Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

#### 05/2015 - 05/2017

No. 204 Pasteur Street Ward 6 Dist.3, Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

#### 05/2014 - 05/2015

Helios Building, Quang Trung Software City, Dist.12, Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

#### Senior Software Engineer

### **Genting Singapore Limited**

∂ http://www.gentingsingapore.com

Genting Singapore and its subsidiaries (the Group) have been at the forefront of gaming and integrated resort development in Australia, the Bahamas, Malaysia, the Philippines, Singapore and the United Kingdom.

#### My responsibility:

- Able to understand of galaxy cinema, CMS, game operating system.
- · Development and refactor functions follow requirements from BA.
- Analyst data and build game operational report for CEO and investor.
- Experience includes both developing on the back-side and front-end, deployment as well
- Applying algorithms, data structures, cryptography and data security.

## Senior Software Engineer of Technology and Ecosystem

#### **Advanced Research Center, Inc**

ARC are committed to building a healthy community and advancing personalized and precision medicine. Together, we can move towards a future where the drug, disease, and person are aligned in treatment towards healthy outcomes.

#### My responsibility:

- Full-stack developer responsibilities include designing and developing highvolume, low-latency applications for mission-critical systems and delivering highavailability and performance
- · Contribute in all phases of the development lifecycle
- · Write well-designed, testable, efficient code
- Ensure designs are in compliance with specifications
- · Prepare and produce releases of software components
- · Able to work well in a fast moving start up environment

## Software Engineer

#### **Dinosys Corporation**

Dinosys develops long-term partnerships with our customers by providing unrivalled experience across various industries and business functions with the highest commitment to product quality and customer service.

## My responsibility:

- Web developer responsibilities include designing, coding, testing, debugging, documenting and supporting all types of applications consistent with established specifications and business requirements to deliver business value
- Build efficient, testable and reusable modules
- Developing pioneering approaches to emerging industry trends
- Solve complex performance problems and architectural challenges
- · Work in a fast-paced, global, agile work environment
- Contribute to development team and help to achieve key business objectives
- · And other related duties being assigned by manager

## Software Engineer

### **Global CyberSoft (Hitachi)**

 ${\cal O}$  https://www.globalcybersoft.com

Hitachi Vantara Vietnam (HVN) (formerly known as Global CyberSoft) is a leading global IT solutions provider founded in California in July 2000, and has been a company of Hitachi Consulting Corporation since October 2014.

## My responsibility:

- Corporate with team to code, test & implement feature based on SRS, BA's document
- Deliver new features: from specification, through development, QA and into final deployment
- Develop oriented documentation

#### **EDUCATION**

08/2010 - 04/2015

## Computer Science Ho Chi Minh University of Technology

## **SELECTED PROJECTS**

## **UP Delivery - Support Tool**

https://updelivery-support-1-2.nxt.unifiedpost.com

A support tool which helps to resolve all issue in delivery flow at UnifiedPost

- Team size: 10 members
- Responsibility: Technical Lead
- Technologies: Java/Spring Boot, Ruby & Rails, ReactJS PostgreSQL AWS

## BattleCity - Blockchain Project (Freelancer)

A ecosystem for gaming, buying & selling NFT.

- Team size: 20 members
- · Responsibility: Team Leader
- Technologies: UnityNodeJS, Nestjs Framework, Angular (12), AWS DynamoDB, RabbitMQ

#### CMS & Admin Portal

A portal to manage all users & game operations Genting's ecosystem

- Team size: 24 members
- Responsibility: Senior Software Engineer
- Technologies: Java/Spring Boot, ReactJS, Microsoft SQL Server, AliCloud (Kubernetes)

### Quickgates (Freelancer)

https://quickgates.io

A Gateway for core blockchain APIs to integrate base module which support deposit, withdraw, minting for SME

- Team Size: 4 members
- · Responsibility: Team leader
- · Technologies: NodeJS, Socket.IO, NestJs, Redis, MySQL

## Anti-Fragility Health (AFH)

An application as Clinic trials system for doctor and patient which tracking patient's health based on biomarker's chart & report

- Team size: 8 members
- Responsibility: Senior Software Engineer
- Technologies: Java/Spring Boot, Angular 4, ReactJS, Microservice (Jhipster), SSO (Auth0), PostgreSQL

## Simple View (CRM)

CRM System for a German Electric Company

- Team size: 8 members
- · Responsibility: Software Engineer
- Technologies: Java, Spring Boot, Thymeleaf, Bootstrap, Elastic Search, Oracle, HTML, CSS, jQuery, Ajax, JSON, XML, Bootstrap (4)

## Open Day Light

2014 - 2015 Global CyberSoft (Hitachi)

Developing functions as set bandwidth, capacity, monitor of virtual switch which implemented by Open flow protocol

- Team size: 12 members
- Responsibility: Java developer
- Technologies: Java Spring MVC Maven, Open Flow, Mini-net, Virtual Switch

#### **LANGUAGES**

Vietnamese Native



English Proficient



#### **INDUSTRY EXPERTISE**

Leadership

Management